

Charles Agyemang

Professional Summary

Ambitious graduate developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Foundational grasp of various Javascript ,CSS and HTML options, development platforms and security requirements .have lived in three different countries (Ghana, Italy, and United Kingdom), speak 3 languages fluently and feel emotionally and culturally attached to all of them thus helping me work in a diverse working environment therefore, it has helped me to build up my confidence and hopefully will carry on.

Professional Experience

Profile Security Ltd - Security Officer

Sheffield

11/2022 - Current

- Acted quickly during emergency situations to reduce opportunity for damage and injury.
- Protected facility and property guests by regularly circulating premises and monitoring surveillance feeds.
- Conducted regular patrols of key areas to spot and control security concerns.
- Greeted guests professionally and courteously to cultivate welcoming atmosphere while making safety top priority.
- Oversaw daily monitoring and patrolled buildings, grounds, and work sites.
- Checked identification of persons entering and exiting facility to eliminate unauthorized visitors.

Austin - Consultant • Software tester

SHEFFIELD

07/2022 - 08/2022

- Wrote and executed effective functional tests and carried out exploratory testing to assess product performance.
- Raised descriptive, concise and useful defect reports and quality standards to showcase testing process.
- Collaborated with personnel to spread good practices, share knowledge and provide tool evaluations and selections support.
- Communicated status updates to stakeholders to widen impact of testing and demonstrate value of optimization program.

- 07765017561
- SHEFFIELD, S3 8FD UNITED KINGDOM
- https://charlesportofolio.netlify.app/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/charles-agyemang-311020109/
- https://github.com/charles3019

Skills

- Good knowledge and understanding of HTML5, CSS and JavaScript (including ES6 and modern frameworks like Vue and React ,express,node,)
- Bootstraps experience
- C# /.NET programming experience
- Java ad C++ programming experience
- Skilled using python and django
- A thorough understanding of version control systems (mainly Git),
 branching, workflows and deployment systems
- A good knowledge of backend development using PHP.
- Advanced understanding of WordPress and the ability to build bespoke themes and plugins
- Experience of modern front-end principles such as web standards, responsive design, web accessibility and page performance
- Experience working from designs within Figma, or similar design software
- Database knowledge,MySQL and mongo DB
- Proactive attitude and eagerness to be challenged
- The ability to work and deliver projects independently but also work well as a

- Planned and estimated test activities to determine effort needed to validate quality of product under test.
- Read, interpreted and followed written test instructions and procedures to accurately test products.
- Checked software beyond testing scripts for interconnected problems not covered by established specifications.
- Checked color, shape, texture and grade of products and materials against established templates, charts, and samples.
- Sampled products to verify compliance with standards
- Provided feedback to production team regarding product quality.
- Followed safety protocols while handling hazardous materials.
- Investigated customer complaints to take necessary corrective actions.
- Operated and maintained testing equipment.
- Monitored product quality at all stages of production process.
- Recommended architectural improvements, design solutions, and integration solutions.
- Provided technical support to production personnel.
- Conducted tests and diagnostic procedures using tools such as analyzers, multimeters, and power supplies.

Yorkshire Electric Scooter - INTERNASHIP - WORDPRESS DEVELOPER

SHEFFIELD

06/2022 - 07/2022

- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot, and other editing software.
- Determined coding requirements for specialized scripts.
- Applied emerging technologies to update and maintain site applicability.
- Ran debugging tools to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity.
- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system compatibility.
- Crafted SEO strategy and intuitive interface for site to achieve prominent rankings across top browser platforms.
- Optimized web applications for speed, scalability and security.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.
- Boosted web traffic by improving navigation and rectifying bottlenecks.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON coding.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.

team

- Good organizational skills and collaboration regarding group work, acquired during periods of study and thanks to various project of invention.
- Adaptable to different situation and able to work under pressure without becoming too overwhelmed or stressed.
- Able to use own initiative to solve problems analytically and practically
- Project management using agile or scrum practice and working with trello as workspace with a team
- Confident user on all Microsoft Office software including word, PowerPoint and Excel
- Microsoft Visual Studio use
- Visual Studio code proficiency

Education

06/2022

SHEFFIELD HALLAM UNIVERSITY

SHEFFIELD

Bachelor of Engineering: SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

2019-2022

Classification: second class Honours (1st division) 2:1

Level 4

- · Component programming
- · Fundamental of computer Architecture
- · Fundamentals of programming
- · Mathematics
- · Professional Experience
- · System Modelling

Level 5

- · Data system for software application
- · Group software development project
- · Object oriented programming
- · Concept and methods of software engineering
- · Web application development

Level 6

- · Application: Architecture and Frameworks
- · Case studies in software design
- · Management of IT projects
- · Programming "Things" (elective module)
- · Projects (technical computing) Final year project

Languages

English, Twi(ghana): Native language

Italian: C

Proficient

06/2019

University of Bedfordshire (Luton) BSc Luton

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science Fy BSc Computer science foundation year

- · Computing system development and data transmission
- · Studying for He (Computing and engineering)
- · Computing system programming
- · Integrated project (computing and engineering)

06/2018

2018 "Conel "college

Enfield (London)

Associate of Applied Science: Applied

Science

Level 3 BTEC: Applied science extended diploma

- · Chemistry
- · Physics
- ·Biology
- · GCSC maths and English

2014

2011- 2014 "Odorico Mattiussi "High School (Italy)

Italy

High School Diploma

- · Business and Economics
- $\cdot \ IT \ in formatics$
- · Physics
- \cdot History
- · Algebra
- ·Biology
- · Geography
- ·Spanish
- · Italian
- · PE

Certifications

Graduate at Sheffield Hallam university BEng Hons in Software Engineering Classification: second class Honours (1st division) 2:1 Level 4